Boaz Blake

BoazBlake@ProtonMail.com | https://boazblake.gitlab.io/identity | cell: 347-420-3251 Motivated - Self Driven - JS Developer

Professional Experience

Front End Web System Developer Empyrean Benefits Solution Houston Tx Aug 2017 – Present Managing and working on multiple projects that include onboarding offshore and new talent and training them on how to port the legacy software into the latest framework.

I am also part of a team that is building out our first enterprise mobile application for both ios and android platforms from nativescript-vue, typescript and graphql.

Jr Front End Web Developer Empyrean Benefits Solution Houston Tx Aug 2016 – Aug 2017
Building in-house applications on demand from scratch as well as porting existing C# PHP and .NET platform/framework and other JS frameworks into one application framework using Typescript and within a functional paradigm.

Part of a team that built from scratch an application that needed to be able to onboard hundreds of employees from hundreds of companies that incorporated an access point for the employee, the company HR rep and also for customer service.

Education

Front End Web Development The Iron Yard, Houston Tx Feb 2016 - April 2016
Intensive 3-month course on HTML, JS and CSS with an emphasis on SOLID principles of OOP.I supplemented my learning with David J. Malan's Harvard CS50 course as well as reading everything I can by Douglas Crockford, Alan Kay, and studying Functional Programming and Lambda-calculus through Brian Lonsdorf FP course and Bartosz Milewski category theory course. Built a fully functioning responsive Event organizer using ReactJS and mongoDB.

PhD Human Space Exploration & Exercise Immunology (epigenetic inheritance) – ABD. University of Houston, Tx September 2011-May 2014

NASA HRP Grant #NNX12AF04G: Studied the effects of gravitational forces on the excitability of the spinal cord.

Bachelor of Science in Sports Medicine James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA August 2007 – May 2010 graduated cum laude

Intensive program focused on Athletic injuries to the professional and amateur athlete.

Background

Tactical Firearms Instructor & Range Safety Officer Top Gun Range, Houston Tx January 2016 – August 2016

Educate public and private sector market on all aspects of gun ownership and usage. Focus on tactical application with integration of armed and unarmed situations.

PhD Research Assistant University of Houston, Tx September 2011 - May 2014

Taught Undergraduate science classes on Biomechanics, Statistics and health and fitness while studying the effects of spaceflight on the nervous system and the genetic effects of environmental stressors on immune function.

Anti-Terrorist Officer/Bodyquard. Israel Oct 2004 – Dec 2005

Provided close protection services for individuals and teams traveling throughout Israel.

Other Info

Married father of one daughter, I enjoy spending time with my family, the outdoors and my freedoms, I am also currently building out from scratch our community website so that our neighborhood can communicate together (https://boazblake.github.io/BACA/#!/about.